

CONTACT

engr.ehtesham736@gmail.com

+923320533780

 \odot

+923320533780

Bhoun Road Near Punjab College Chakwal , Chakwal

SKILLS

Time Management

Excellent Communication

Project Management

Team Work

Leadership Qualities

Critical Thinker

Problem Solver

Creative and Self Motivated

Field Investigation Skills

SOFTWARES

MS office (Word, Excel, Power point)

Auto Cad 2D & 3D

MD Solid

Primavera

Matlab

ЕТАВ

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH

URDU

PUNJABI

ENGR. EHTESHAM SAEED

CAREER OBJECTIVE:

I am highly self-motivated, focused and innovative Civil Engineer with one year field experience. I have a passion for learning and developing new and existing skills and I enjoy problem-solving using established analytical methods and engineering principles. I am keen to secure a challenging role in an engineering firm that offers early responsibilities and a progressive career path.

WORK EXPERIENCE

***** KB CONSTRUCTION & CO.

Designation: Civil Engineer | Aug. 2020 to till date

Responsibilities

- Working with clients, local authorities and external agencies on various projects.
- Creating 2D drawing using AutoCAD.
- Performing site test on different site works.
- Regularly check the progress and performance of the site work according to the schedule.
- Providing technical advice and solving different problems on site.
- Checking plans, drawings and quantities for accuracy of calculations.
- Managing budgets and other project resources.
- Maintaining the safety on site through promoting a safety culture.

❖ FRONTIER WORKS ORGANIZATION (FWO)

Designation: Internee | June 2019 - July 2019

Job Responsibilities

- Visit the sites and checked the work progress.
- Understanding weekly and monthly progress reports.
- Learn response letter writing and preparation of bidding process.
- Performing different field tests and then calculate the final results.

EDUCATION

BSC - Civil Engineering (2016-2020)

From University of Engineering and Technology Lahore

FSC - Pre-Engineering (2014-2016)

From Punjab College Chakwal

MATRIC (2012-2014)

From Chakwal Grammar School Chakwal

MAJOR SUBJECTS STUDIED

- Structural Engineering
- Hydraulic Engineering
- Geotechnical Engineering
- Project Management
- Transportation Engineering
- Environmental Engineering
- Irrigation Engineering
- Surveying
- Design of Steel Structures

HOBBIES



Travelling





Newspaper Cooking







Book reading

Gardening

Hiking

REFERENCE

Will be provided on your demand

FINAL YEAR PROJECT

- Flood routing of Mangla reservoir using Hec-ResSim
- Performance evaluation of Mangla reservoir using Hec-ResSim
- To develop the flood hydrographs of the reservoir by Hec-ResSim
- To compare the results of before and after the raising of Mangla reservoir using Hec-ResSim model

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Works as the Vice president of Hult prize in UET.
- Organize the Hult prize event in campus and won the best regional on campus award and got 3rd position all over the world.
- Works with ACI CESA student chapter in UET and organize different bridge building competitions in UET.
- Participated in Bridge building competition and won the best bridge design award.
- Participated in concrete ball competition and won the award of high strength concrete ball.
- Awarded with different certificates of appreciation in university.
- Lead the Final Year Project group and won the best group leader of FYP.
- Lead the Survey Camp group and won the best survey group award.
- Attend the sessions of Youth Leadership Parliament (YLP) at LUMS university and awarded with appreciation certificate.
- Attend LUMAN at Beaconhouse National University (BNU) and LUMS University.
- Organize and attend a lot of seminars in UET and also in other universities as well.

AWARDS

- Top position holder in School
- Top position holder in College
- Hult Prize winner
- Bridge building competition winner
- Survey camp group winner
- Final year project winner
- Best leader award winner in YLP
- Concrete block competition winner
- FRC concrete ball competition winner

INTEREST & STRENGTHS

- Motivational and Team spirit
- Ability to work under stress environment
- Innovative and having solution finding approach
- Design of Reinforced Concrete Structures